Ali-Taabesh Sayyed

■ 469-955-1847 | Malitsayyed@gmail.com | DinkedIn | GitHub | US Citizen

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 1 year of experience and worked in startup environments. A fast learner and problem-solver with strong analytical/interpersonal skills. Strong project and time management skills to exceed expectations. Biochemistry (STEM) major with 4.0 GPA Summa Cum Laude.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Go (Golang), HTML, CSS (SCSS), SQL
- Frameworks & Tools: Django, Angular, React, Git, GitHub, N8N (Workflow Automation), Dockers, Kubernetes, Terraform, Virtual Machines, Google Cloud Platform, Google App Scripts, vim
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite
- Development: Data Structures & Algorithms (DSA), Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Functional Programming, REST APIs
- Other: HTTP Networking, IP Subnetting, Debugging, Problem-Solving, Analytical Abilities, Prompt Engineering, Agentic Frameworks, AI-Agents

Information Technology

- Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X & Linux (Ubuntu & Kali)
- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel), Google Suite (Docs, Slides, Sheets), Adobe (Premier, Photoshop, After Effects)

Communication & Interpersonal

- Excellent Communication Skills, Persuasive Messaging, Storytelling, Active Listening, Conflict Management Skills
- Team player with a positive attitude, confident self-starter, entrepreneurial and risk-taking ability

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer- BRAIN

Nov 2024 – Present

- Architected and implemented automated data pipelines for voice AI solutions while collaborating with backend developers to ensure seamless integration with our Golang microservices architecture.
- Developed full-stack voice AI integration solutions, engineering both the data processing backend and interactive frontend portals that drove client engagement and satisfaction.
- Demonstrated exceptional technical adaptability by independently mastering complex backend architecture, implementing custom automation solutions, and rapidly learning new technologies to deliver seamless client experiences in a fast-paced startup environment.

Full Stack Developer- Legal Pro

Aug 2024 - Nov 2024

- Worked on full stack development, enabling lawyers to efficiently manage clients, cases, and communications.
- Developed WebSocket-based messaging to support real-time chat functionality, providing a user experience similar to WhatsApp Web.
- Leveraged Django for backend functionality, including WebSocket integration and database management, and Angular for a responsive, user-friendly frontend interface.

Biomedical Nano-Devices Research Assistant/ Biology TA

June 2018 – May 2021

- Facilitated online classes, curated content, fostered discussions, and prepared students for exams.
- Conducted experiments and data analysis for a wearable sweat-based nano-sensor for detecting inflammatory proteins.

PROJECTS

View my developer portfolio site: https://www.alitsayyed-portfolio.vercel.app/

Full Stack

• Developed a full stack (Django, Angular, PostgreSQL) Mock Trust Pilot site for freelancer reviews called <u>LancerRank</u>. Strong understanding of REST APIs.

Back End

• Developed a Go back-end server for an RSS aggregator with user authentication and efficient feed collection.

Front End

• Created an <u>Amazon clone site</u> using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Strong fundamental understanding of the DOM, how to manipulate it, and how frontend frameworks build upon it.

Data Structure and Algorithms

• Examples are eight puzzle solver using A* search algorithm, percolation determination with union find, and Kd-Trees.

EDUCATION

University of Princeton/Helsinki Online Course - Computer Science

Sept 2023-May 2024

• Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Java, Python

The University of Texas at Dallas - B.S. Biochemistry (4.0 GPA Summa Cum Laude)

Aug 2018 - May 2022

AWARDS

Dean's List, Richardson, TX

Aug 2018 – May 2022

• Maintained top 10% GPA in the School of Natural Sciences and Mathematics.

AES Distinction Scholarship, Richardson, TX

Awarded a full-ride scholarship to high school students with competitive grades.